### NICOLA ZANON

Front-End Developer, SEO & Web Designer.

# .01 CONTACTS

www.nicola-zanon.com
(+44) 077 488 870 22
nicola.zanon86@gmail.com
SE13 7SE

# 02 ABOUT ME

I am an italian web designer who decided to move to the UK to get a chance of working with the best people in the web industry.

### STRENGHTS

High attention to details.

Fast learner and problem solver.

### CAREER HISTORY

### Ignite Hospitality Marketing

(09/2014 - 10/2015)

### Front-end Developer (Head of Team)

Responsible for developing mobile-first Wordpress powered website and improving team efficiency.

- Front-End Development
- Wordpress
- UX
- Performance Optimisation
- SEC
- Managing Tasks

### Photobox Ltd

( 03/2014 - 09/2014 )

### Developer (Integration team)

Responsible for developing and integrating new features on their Custom  $E\text{-}\mathrm{commerce}$  platform.

- Front-End Development
- Responsive HTML email development
- Perl, Mason

### Web design teacher

( 2012 - Present )

### Teacher

Teaching privately to different students the principles of graphics, web design and the Adobe suite:

- Web Development
- Graphic design
- Adobe suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign)

### Freelancer

( 2011 - Present )

### Wordpress Developer - SEO

Working as a freelance on several projects, including web design, front-end development and devising SEO strategies based around specific keywords.

- Designing Responsive web sites for several clients
- Writing cross-browser HTML5, CSS & Javascript
- Developing usable and clean Website that have a consistent look and feel throughout all web properties
- Working on budget restrictions
- Coding semantic web sites with strong focus on SEO factors
- SEO

### Poli DIstillerie

(04/2012 - 01/2014)

### SEO and Web Consultant

Responsible for working on a range of projects, re-designing the company websites and promoted the brand on the web.

- Co-designed the company web sites
- Developed SEO strategies
- Managed and promoted the Company's E-Commerce
- Created banners, promotional pages for events and online content.
- Monitored and reported online success based on ROI

### CAREER STATEMENT

I feel my greatest strengths are firstly my several different experiences on web related projects where I've learnt to work on various aspects of the matter.

Secondly my skill on developing mobile-first responsive web site.

Thirdly my real passion for the Web as a whole, something that allows me to spot trends and develop best practice processes.

### KEY SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS3, JS/jQuery, SASS/LESS, PHP
- Deep knowledge of Responsive web design process and related issues
- Awareness of the Web Development industry and new technology
- Knowledge of front-end developmnet and cross browser compatibility issue
- Can manage multiple projects in a fast-paced, deadline-driven environment
- Confident, friendly and easy to get along with.

### AREA OF EXPERTIES PERSONAL SKILLS

- Responsive Web Design
- Front-end development
- Graphic design
- Prototyping
- Search Engine Optimiza-
- tion
- Web marketing

Troubleshooting

Strategies

- Analytic and reporting

- Creative thinker
- Team player - Hard worker
- Attention to detail
- Reliable
- Analytical
- Problem solving

### SOFTWARE & TOOLS

- Wordpress
- Gulp/Grunt
- GIT
- MAMP
- Analytic tools
- Sketch
- Adobe Suite
- Google AdWords
- Excel

### ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

### Milan Business School "Sole24 ore" (2012)

Professional training course in Web Marketing and new technology for communication.

### Padua University (2005 - 2010)

Master of Arts in Social Psychology and organizations.